

WASEEM ABBAS

Android | Flutter | KMP Developer

+92 302 1888898



engr.waseemabbas8@gmail.com



/waseemabbas8

/waseemabbas8



waseemabbas.com

A results-driven and customer-focused Software Engineer who can think "out of the box". Love creating software solutions. 5 years' Experience in Mobile app development (Android native + Flutter). Expert in Kotlin, Java, Dart, C#, and KTOR with PostgreSql database. Good practical knowledge of modern tools and technologies used in mobile apps development. Strong written and verbal communications.

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineering GC University Faisalabad CGPA: 3.72

SKILLS

- ✓ Android App Development
- ✓ Flutter App Development
- ✓ KMP & KTOR Backend Development
- ✓ GitHub VCS
- √ Team Leadership
- ✓ Problem Solving

TOOLS

- ✓ MVVM, MVC, MVI
- ✓ Kotlin (Android, KTOR)
- ✓ Java (Android)
- ✓ Android Jetpack
- ✓ DI with KOIN/HILT
- ✓ ExoPlayer (Android, Flutter)
- ✓ Retrofit (Android, Flutter)
- ✓ Dart (Flutter Apps)
- ✓ GetX (Flutter)
- ✓ KTOR for REST APIs for both client & Server
- ✓ KTOR Expose (backend)
- ✓ PostgreSql

EXPERIENCE

ANDROID | FLUTTER TEAM LEAD

2021-PRESENT

DEVCREW/IO, PAKISTAN

KTOR Backend Developer

Building REST APIs with KTOR, KTOR Expose and PostgreSql

Sizzle KMP based project, currently working on it

Android Team Lead

Building android apps and creating software architecture and code reviews

- Turning Point Video/audio podcasts (Android).
- Bible Project Bible reader, video/audio podcasts (Android)
- Final Touch photo editing app (Android)
- WhatsApp Sticker sticker maker app (Android)
- Flutter Developer
 - Meganova Gaming warm up app (Flutter)
 - GoWhee Kid friendly travel app (Flutter)

ANDROID TEAM LEAD

2019-2021

SOFT SOLUTIONS, PAKISTAN

As a team leader creating a project structure and creating customized libraries or utilities for team members. Developing apps with latest tools and design framework (MVVM). Version controlling of each project through GitHub.

- People-i Android app to execute HR services in real time
- Bookryt An appointment booking platform for customers and saloons
- Mateam Homemade food ordering app, further more includes selling/purchasing of Vehicles, Houses and services
- CampusPro A class attendance system, can manage timetables and student's data
- BrainUp Online test preparation app with numerous tests for all levels and fields
- Results App allow users to check all Pakistan Boards and universities results online
- Tutors Find authorized tutors online. Realtime chat between teachers & students

ANDROID DEVELOPER

2017-2019

THETA SOLUTIONS, PAKISTAN

Building Apps using JAVA and Kotlin with Android Architecture Components.

Sialkot Bazar Customer oriented e-commerce platform to take care shopping needs